<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>MehrdadLinux</title>
  <link href="http://Opsnit.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Opsnit.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-22T02:44:12+04:30</updated>
  <id>http://Opsnit.com/</id>
  <author>
      <name>MehrdadLinux</name></name>
  <email>MehrdadLinux@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  
  <entry>
    <title>remove password from pdf files </title>
    <link href="http://Opsnit.com/2016/03/22/remove-password-from-pdf-files-.html"/>
    <updated>2016-03-22T00:00:00+04:30</updated>
    <id>http://Opsnit.com/</id>/2016/03/22/remove-password-from-pdf-files-</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://cdn.osxdaily.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/password-protect-pdf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pdfpass&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;hello my frind today i have another problem with password security
&lt;br /&gt;i found pdf in net that protected by password i dont like it because
&lt;br /&gt;after a days i forget where i downloaded and i loss a password
&lt;br /&gt;we have very good solution in linux
&lt;br /&gt;you must only install pdftk from repositori
&lt;br /&gt;apt-get install pdftk
&lt;br /&gt;after that use pdftk like this
&lt;br /&gt;pdftk yourpdf password protect.pdf input_pw yourpassword output ./1.pdf
&lt;br /&gt;solved&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>MehrdadLinux</name>
      <uri>http://Opsnit.com/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to move VirtualBox VM’s To Other Drive</title>
    <link href="http://Opsnit.com/2016/03/18/how-to-move-vbox-vms.html"/>
    <updated>2016-03-18T00:00:00+03:30</updated>
    <id>http://Opsnit.com/</id>/2016/03/18/how-to-move-vbox-vms</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/graphics/vbox_logo2_gradient.png&quot; alt=&quot;vbox&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;today for a second time i must move my Vbox vms to another location , because i don’t have enough space in that location.
VirtualBox have problem to move VM’s because if you can not introduce your VM’s to VirtualBox again you can not use it or you have hard way to pass.
i solve this problem 2 years a go . and i dont document it know when i have this problem a gain i cannot remember how solve it :|
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;i promise to my self if i solve it a gain i write my solution in blog :)))
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;ok first you shut down all of your vm
it is very important and now close your vbox move all your vm to other location you want
now open vbox you see all off your vm loss a path right click on vm an now remove them
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.pcstats.com/articleimages/201207/win8virtualization_vb18.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;remove_vbox&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;go to tools option and click on add find your vm and add it in your vbox problem solved
its was too easy keep it simple :D
have fun&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>MehrdadLinux</name>
      <uri>http://Opsnit.com/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>software freedom day</title>
    <link href="http://Opsnit.com/2015/08/29/software-freedom-day.html"/>
    <updated>2015-08-29T00:00:00+04:30</updated>
    <id>http://Opsnit.com/</id>/2015/08/29/software-freedom-day</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;SFD is a worldwide celebration of Free and Open Source Software (FOSS). Our goal in this celebration is to educate the worldwide public about the benefits of using high quality FOSS in education, in government, at home, and in business – in short, everywhere! The non-profit organization Software Freedom International coordinates SFD at a global level, providing support, giveaways and a point of collaboration, but volunteer teams around the world organize the local SFD events to impact their own communities.
&lt;img src=&quot;/res/software-freedom-day-2011-logo300px.png&quot; alt=&quot;software-freedom-day-2011&quot; /&gt;
Many thanks to our Sponsors and Supporters without whom we could not make such an event happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Find out more about Software Freedom International and SFD.
Read about how Software Freedom underpins your human rights from our former President, Pia Waugh
Also find out more about Free Software.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vision &amp;amp; Objectives
Our vision is to empower all people to freely connect, create and share in a digital world that is participatory, transparent, and sustainable.
Objectives&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To celebrate software freedom and the people behind it&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To foster a general understanding of software freedom, and encourage adoption of free software and open standards&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To create more equal access to opportunities through the use of participatory technologies&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To promote constructive dialogue on responsibilities and rights in the information society&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To be inclusive of organizations and individuals that share our Vision&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To be pragmatic, transparent, and responsible as an organisation&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>MehrdadLinux</name>
      <uri>http://Opsnit.com/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Linux Users' Group (LUG)</title>
    <link href="http://Opsnit.com/2015/08/29/linux-users-group-lug.html"/>
    <updated>2015-08-29T00:00:00+04:30</updated>
    <id>http://Opsnit.com/</id>/2015/08/29/linux-users-group-lug</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Linux User Group or Linux Users’ Group (LUG) or GNU/Linux User Group (GLUG) is a private, generally non-profit or not-for-profit organization that provides support and/or education for Linux users, particularly for inexperienced users. The term commonly refers to local groups that meet in person, but is also used to refer to online support groups that may have members spread over a very wide area and which do not organize, or are not dependent on, physical meetings. Many LUGs encompass FreeBSD and other free Unix-based operating systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>MehrdadLinux</name>
      <uri>http://Opsnit.com/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hackerspace</title>
    <link href="http://Opsnit.com/2015/08/29/hackerspace.html"/>
    <updated>2015-08-29T00:00:00+04:30</updated>
    <id>http://Opsnit.com/</id>/2015/08/29/hackerspace</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/res/Hackerspaces.org.logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hackerspaces.orglogo&quot; /&gt;
A hackerspace (also referred to as a hacklab, makerspace or hackspace) is a community-operated workspace where people with common interests, often in computers, machining, technology, science, digital art or electronic art, can meet, socialize and collaborate.[1] Hackerspaces have also been compared to other community-operated spaces with similar aims and mechanisms such as Fab Lab, Men’s Sheds, and with commercial “for profit” companies such as TechShop.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>MehrdadLinux</name>
      <uri>http://Opsnit.com/about/</uri>
    </author>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
